# **AKSHATH SIVAPRASAD**

#### **SUMMARY**

I am self-driven, dedicated, a team player, and a quick learner. I am willing to learn anything to get the job done. I like to code for fun; I've participated in several hackathons and competitions such as USACO (gold medalist) and worked on various personal projects. I like to spend my free time rock climbing and singing.

### CONTACT

in /in/akshathsivaprasad

### **EDUCATION**

University of California, Berkeley Electrical Engineering & Computer Science 2018

# **SKILLS**

**LANGUAGES:** Java, C#, Python, C, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Scheme **SELECTED COURSES:** 

Computer Security,
Machine Structures,
Database Systems,
Efficient Algorithms, Data Science,
Data Structures, Artificial Intelligence,
Operating Systems, Networking,
Web Design

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### Microsoft

Software Development Intern

May 2017 to Aug 2017

I implemented issuer-based certificate pinning in order to reduce the inherent manual work and code deployments involved with certificate expiry. I also developed a subject name-to-service identity mapping and a detection system to track rogue certificates and identify certificate misuse. Required knowledge: C#, certificate-based authentication.

#### **Apptio**

Software Development Intern

May 2015 to Aug 2016

I worked on two main projects over two summers. The first was a complete revamp of the healthcheck system, transitioning from Pingdom to an internal logging utility backed by Splunk. The second involved developing new features for AdHoc Query, an on-the-fly chart/table manipulation tool. Mostly backend, but required some UI/translator works as well. Required knowledge: Java, JavaCC, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, XML.

## Science Infinity

Founder

Aug 2011 to Current

I am the founder of Science Infinity, a nonprofit organization aimed towards broadening the academic horizons of elementary and middle school students. Science Infinity has experienced explosive growth, comprising of hundreds of students in 5 states. Members consistently win at national-level competitions. I coordinated weekly meetings, managed a large volunteer pool, and helped host state-level chapters of competitions such as You Be The Chemist! and North South Foundation.

#### MetaCAPTCHA

Software Security Intern

May 2013 to Sep 2013

MetaCAPTCHA is an anti-spam service designed to protect web applications by employing metamorphism borne from the use of both CAPTCHAs and proof-of-work puzzles. I primarily worked on integration tools as well as a solution to replay attacks. I presented my work at the 2013 ASE Symposium. Required knowledge: PHP, JavaScript, Linux-based systems.

# **PROJECTS**

#### Gitlet

A basic version of a popular version control system, Git, implemented from scratch in Java. Employs SHA-256 hashing and GZip compression, and includes features such as merge, interactive rebase, remote push/pull etc.

# WordamentPlayer

I used Java and JNA to write WordamentPlayer, a bot designed to play Wordament, an online Boggle-like game in which players compete to find the most words in a 4x4 board.

#### Toggle

Toggle is a combination between the games Tetris and Boggle. Required knowledge: JavaScript, HTML, CSS.